<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Todd Emerson</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Todd Emerson</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Outsider: Returning Home to Central Virginia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/outsider-richmondenergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/outsider-richmondenergy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been using the internet since early 1990, before many people had even heard of it. At Virginia Commonwealth University, I received an undergraduate grant from the State Council for Higher Education in Virginia (SCHEV) that allowed me to explore my curiosity about the internet and computers. With this opportunity, I built an application that allowed students to submit, review, and revise their papers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, outside of academia, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see a way to apply my passion for technology in the Richmond area. After graduating from VCU in the early 90s, I relocated from Richmond due to the limited opportunities for tech enthusiasts like myself. This move transformed me from an &amp;ldquo;insider&amp;rdquo; within my small Richmond-area university community to an &amp;ldquo;outsider&amp;rdquo; with no connections in the growing Seattle tech landscape. At that time, Microsoft dominated Seattle&amp;rsquo;s tech scene, but there was an emerging narrative of software companies establishing themselves in the region, often because of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s presence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speaking in Objectives: A Professional Parable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/2024-05-10-speaking-in-objectives-a-professional-parable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 16:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-outsider/2024-05-10-speaking-in-objectives-a-professional-parable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following story was one my Dad told me many times as a reminder that it is often most effective to explain what you&amp;rsquo;re trying to accomplish rather than how you want something done. In my early days as a Program Manager, I had a thoughtful manager who took the time to sit with me and put it in the terms of explaining the &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rdquo; rather than the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t dive deep and work through the complexities of problems, but that we should avoid defining the solution in details that we do not necessarily control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
